# Khalil A. Niser

### **OBJECTIVES**

Phone: (786) 312-3794

Motivated, self driven displays a desire to take initiatives while working. Enjoys a team environment, demonstrates success in individual tasks, with effective, Communication, and problem-solving skills.

Proficient in multiple OOP languages. Most extensively Java. Have been working with Java for over a decade created multiple projects. Demonstrate a comprehensive knowledge in Data Structures and algorithms, as well as Big-O Notations and Time Complexities.

#### **SKILLS AND STRENGTHS**

- Extensive knowledge in Java, C++, C#, C, JavaScript, HTML, CSS...
- Extensive knowledge in Database (SQL, and MS Access).
- Worked with Medical Devices (IQ, OQ, PQ)
- Documented protocols (TMV, ATMV, VTMV, SOP and SOD).

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Data Structures and Algorithms**

### **Big-O-Notations**

Complete Understanding of Big-O-Notations. Time Complexities.

#### **Sorting Algorithms**

• Proficient in Data Structures and corresponding sorting algorithms. Bubble Sort, Selection Sort, Insertion Sort, Shell Sort, Recursive Algorithm, Merge Sort, Quick Sort, Counting Sort, Radix Sort, Stable Counting Sort, Sorting Arrays Using the JDK.

# Med Device Quality Engineer

Edwards LifeSciences,

July, 2017 – August, 2018 Tel Aviv, Israel

Email: kaliniser@gmail.com

- Create and validate deliverable such as validation project plans, risk assessments, validation (IQ, OQ, PQ) protocols, commission plans, and validate summary reports etc.
- Validated different types of test methods (Attribute Test Method, Variable Destructive Test Method, Variable Non-Destructive Test Method, Analytical Test Method and Inspection Test Methods, Mechanical and Dimensional Test Methods)
- Maintained and updated Validation Master Plan and related documentation
- Performed Gripper and Tube Welding for Break Torque Force measurements.
- Demonstrated effectiveness of the Physical Test Method for tensile testing.
- Tools used: (Mark 10 Torque Gauge, IC Masters, Wire Masters, Universal Testing Machine (UTM), Grips, and Load Cells.

# **Computer System Validation Engineer IMQA**

LS Solutions (Consulting Firm)
ConvaTec Group

October 2018 – August 2021 Chicago, IL (USA)

- Create qualification and validation deliverable such as validation project plans, risk assessments, validation (IQ, OQ, PQ) protocols, commissioning plans, commissioning and validation summary reports etc.
- Validated different types of test methods Attribute Test Method Validation (ATMV), Variable
  Test Method Validation (VTMV) Variable Destructive Test Method, Variable Non-Destructive
  Test Method, Analytical Test Methods and Inspection Test Methods, Mechanical and
  Dimensional Test Methods.
- Maintained and updated Validation Master Plan and related documentation
- Authored and executed IQ/OQ/PQ protocols and wrote reports
- Responsible for entire TFIQ creation and executions

#### Inbound/Outbound

Amazon Prime

Novenber 2021 – August, 2023 *Portland*, OR (USA)

- Conduct daily inbound, Outbound of Merchandise as well as daily orders and deliverable
- Maintain and updated Validation Master Plan and related documentation
- Inbound, Outbound, Blind Cycle Count

#### **EDUCATION**

Languages: English, Spanish, and Arabic

**Keiser University**, Pembroke Pines, Florida Bachelors of Science: Software Engineering

Graduate: 2017

• Student Government Association (SGA)-Vice-President

Leadership Distinction Program (LDP)

Awards:

**EPA Certified Universal**Certificate No: 549558568330